Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals WEB.ARC.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Hayden, Tom Archived Website, Aug 20, 2010 - ongoing; Hayden, Tom
  Tom Hayden was one of the founders of Students for a Democratic Society and a principal author of its Port Huron Statement. After over forty years of activism, politics and writing, Tom Hayden still is a leading voice for ending the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, erasing sweatshops, saving the environment, and reforming politics through greater citizen participation. Currently he is writing and advocating for US Congressional hearings on exiting Afghanistan. He is the current O'Brien Distinguished Professor of Legal Studies at Scripps College in Claremont, California, where he teaches classes on street gangs and urban politics and the Long Wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.
  Radicals |z United States.
- Haynes, John Earl Archived Website, Jul 9, 2009; Haynes, John Earl.
  American Communism and Anticommunism: A Historian’s Bibliography and Guide to the Literature, compiled, edited and periodically updated by John Earl Haynes, 20th Century Political Historian, Manuscript Division, Library of Congress. Contains almost 10,000 entries as of 2009.
  Anti-communist movements |z United States |v Bibliography.; Communism |z United States |v Bibliography.
- Hightower, Jim (Hightower Lowdown) Archived Website, Jan 8, 2012 - ongoing; Hightower, Jim, 1943-
  The Hightower Lowdown, founded by Jim Hightower in 1999, is a monthly populist newsletter that features investigative reporting and humorous and opinion articles on current issues. The website and newsletter have over 130,000 subscribers.
  Electronic journals.; Populism.
- International Journal of Žižek Studies Archived Website, Nov 3, 2010 - ongoing; Zizek, Slavoj, International Journal of Žižek Studies (IJŽS)
  Slavoj Žižek is a radical philosopher and social critic, inspired by Marxism and post-modernism. The International Journal of Žižek Studies (IJŽS) is an online, peer-reviewed academic journal devoted to investigating, elaborating, and critiquing the work of Slavoj Žižek, and is a member of Open Humanities Press, an international open access publishing collective in critical and cultural theory.
  Zizek, Slavoj; Philosophers.; Philosophy, Marxist; Postmodernism
- Ireland, Doug (Direland) Archived Website, Jul 21, 2010-Apr 14, 2013; Ireland, Doug
  Direland is a political blog that contains analysis and commentary on current events, written by Doug Ireland. Ireland is an American journalist and blogger who writes about politics, power, media, and also about gay issues. He is the U.S. correspondent for the French political- investigative weekly Bakchich, for which he also writes a weekly column, and he is also the Contributing Editor for International Affairs of Gay City News.
  News web sites |z United States.
- Klein, Naomi, 1970- Archived Website, Dec 2, 2008 - ongoing; Klein, Naomi, 1970-
  Naomi Klein (b. 1970) is an award-winning journalist, syndicated columnist and author of the books, The Shock Doctrine: The Rise of Disaster Capitalism and No Logo: Taking Aim at the Brand Bullies. Naomi Klein writes a regular column for The Nation and The Guardian that is syndicated internationally. She also publishes the free online newsletter Naomi Klein's Newsletter.
  Anti-globalization movement.; Radicals |z Canada.; Social justice.
- Kucinich, Dennis, 1946- Archived Website, Aug 16, 2009 - ongoing; Kucinich, Dennis J., 1946-
  Dennis Kucinich (b. 1946) is a member of the U.S. Congress' House of Representatives, from Ohio's 10th Congressional district (Cleveland), and formerly the Mayor of Cleveland, and is known for his radical politics. He was also a candidate for the Democratic nomination for President of the United States in the 2004 and 2008 presidential elections. This is his official website.
  Cleveland (Ohio) |x Politics and government.; Ohio--Politics and government.; Radicals |z United States.; United States |x Politics and government.
- Kunstler, William Archived Website, Jul 23, 2009 - Mar 14, 2010; Kunstler, Sarah
  This is the website of the film, Disturbing the Universe, created Emily Kunstler and Sarah Kunstler, which explores the life of their father, William Kunstler, who was a radical civil rights lawyer. In the 1960s and 70s, Kunstler fought for civil rights with Martin Luther King Jr. and represented the famed "Chicago 8" activists who protested the Vietnam War. The website contains information on the film. It was last updated in 2010.
  Kunstler, William M. (William Moses), 1919-1995; Kunstler, William M. (William Moses), 1919-1995 |x in motion.; Lawyers |x Political activity |z United States.; pictures.
- Lakoff, George Archived Website, Jun 1, 2012 - ongoing; Lakoff, George
  George P. Lakoff (1941-) is an American cognitive linguist and professor of linguistics at the University of California, Berkeley, where he has taught since 1972. He is most famous for his ideas about the centrality of metaphor to human thinking, political behavior and society. He is particularly famous for his concept of the "embodied mind", which he has written about in relation to mathematics. In recent years he has applied his work to the realm of politics, exploring this in his books. He was the founder of the now defunct progressive think tank the Rockridge Institute. Moral Politics (1996, revisited in 2002) gives book-length consideration to the conceptual metaphors that Lakoff sees as present in the minds of American "liberals" and "conservatives". The book is a blend of cognitive science and political analysis. Lakoff...argues for the superiority of the liberal vision. Lakoff argues that the differences in opinions between liberals and conservatives follow from the fact that they subscribe with different strength to two different metaphors about the relationship of the state to its citizens. Both, he claims, see governance through metaphors of the family. Conservatives would subscribe more strongly and more often to a model that he calls the "strict father model" and has a family structured around a strong, dominant "father" (government), and assumes that the "children" (citizens) need to be disciplined to be made into responsible "adults" (morality, self-financing). In contrast, Lakoff argues that liberals place more support in a model of the family, which he calls the "nurturant parent model", based on "nurturant values", where both "mothers" and "fathers" work to keep the essentially good "children" away from "corrupting influences" (pollution, social injustice, poverty, etc.). Lakoff says that most people have a blend of both metaphors applied at different times, and that political speech works primarily by invoking these metaphors. Lakoff further argues that one of the reasons liberals have had difficulty since the 1980s is that they have not been as aware of their own guiding metaphors, and have too often accepted conservative terminology framed in a way to promote the strict father metaphor.Tax relief for example, implies explicitly that taxes are an affliction, something someone would want "relief" from. To use the terms of another metaphoric worldview, Lakoff insists, is to unconsciously support it. Liberals must support linguistic think tanks in the same way that conservatives do if they are going to succeed in appealing to those in the country who share their metaphors.
  Linguistics |x Political aspects.
- Lamont, Corliss Archived Website, Jul 16, 2010; Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.
  Corliss Lamont (1902-1995) is a 20th century American hero whose independent thinking challenged prevailing ideas in philosophy, economics, religion, patriotism, world peace and the exercise of our cherished civil liberties. Corliss Lamont was born to Wall Street wealth, yet he championed the cause of the working class, and was derided as a "Socialist" and a "traitor to his class". Corliss Lamont's Humanist belief that earthlings have evolved without supernatural intervention and are responsible for their own survival on this planet caused traditionalists to label him a "godless atheist". Corliss Lamont's patriotic insistence that the United States maintain a productive relationship with the Soviet Union in the face of prevailing rabid anti-communist hysteria earned him the accusation by Senator Joseph McCarthy of being "un-American". Corliss Lamont was a philosopher, author and poet who carried several landmark cases to the courts successfully, including a suitagainst the United States Postmaster General which was taken to the U.S. Supreme Court. The high court's decision was in Dr. Lamont's favor. He taught a course in Humanism at Columbia University.
  Humanism.; Humanists |z United States.
- Law Office of Elizabeth M. Fink Archived Website, Apr 10, 2014-ongoing; Fink, Elizabeth
  This is the website for the Law Office of Elizabeth M. Fink, a civil rights and criminal defense attorney. Fink has worked on a number of cases including as the defense attorney for the Attica Prison riot class action suit. She also defended Silvia Baraldini, Dhoruba Bin-Wahad, and the United Freedom Front. The website also contains information on the other attorneys in the law office, Sarah Kunstler and Rebecca Heinegg.
  Attica Prison.; Legal assistance to prisoners |z United States.; Legal services |z New York (State) |z New York.; Women lawyers.
- Lazar, Ernie Archived Website, Apr 15, 2011 - ongoing; Lazar, Ernie
  This website contains the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests Ernie Lazar requested from the FBI and other agencies. He has requested over 8900 FOIA requests totaling over 600,000 pages. Lazar is particularly interested in documents related to the John Birch Society and organizations and individuals recommended by the society. Organizations include the American Association for the United Nations, American Civil Liberties Union, Americans For Democratic Action, American Friends Service Committee, Anti-Defamation League of B’nai B’rith, Council on Foreign Relations, CORE, Foreign Policy Association, Highlander Folk School, League of Women Voters, NAACP, National Committee For A Sane Nuclear Policy, National Council of Churches, National Education Association, National Student Association, National Urban League, United World Federalists, UNESCO, UNICEF. Lazar also collects FOIA requests related to the Communist Party USA. The website contains his research based on the requests.
  John Birch Society.; Anti-communist movements; Communism.; Domestic intelligence |z United States.; Right and left (Political science)
- Lazar, Ernie on Communist Party USA Archived Website, May 2, 2012; Lazar, Ernie
  This website contains the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests Ernie Lazar requested from the FBI and other agencies. He has requested over 8900 FOIA requests totaling over 600,000 pages. Lazar is particularly interested in documents related to the John Birch Society and organizations and individuals recommended by the society. Organizations include the American Association for the United Nations, American Civil Liberties Union, Americans For Democratic Action, American Friends Service Committee, Anti-Defamation League of B’nai B’rith, Council on Foreign Relations, CORE, Foreign Policy Association, Highlander Folk School, League of Women Voters, NAACP, National Committee For A Sane Nuclear Policy, National Council of Churches, National Education Association, National Student Association, National Urban League, United World Federalists, UNESCO, UNICEF. Lazar also collects FOIA requests related to the Communist Party USA. The website contains his research based on the requests. The updates for this page are contained in the main ernie124102 captures.
  Anti-communist movements |z United States.; Communism |z United States.
- Maddow, Rachel Archived Website, Feb 26, 2012 - ongoing; Maddow, Rachel
  Rachel Anne Maddow (1973-) is an American television host and political commentator. Maddow hosts a nightly television show, The Rachel Maddow Show, on MSNBC. Her syndicated talk radio program, The Rachel Maddow Show, aired on Air America Radio. Maddow is the first openly gay anchor of a prime-time news program in the United States.
  Alternative radio broadcasting.; Mass media criticism.; Television broadcasting.
- MalcolmX.com Archived Website, Aug 11, 2010 - ongoing; Estate of Malcolm X.
  The Official Web Site of Malcolm X has everything you want to know about this historical figure. Read his biography and read inspirational quotes from this talented speaker. Browse the photo gallery for pictures of Malcolm X throughout his life. The Community section is a great place to download FREE desktop wallpapers and screen savers. Visit other Web sites dedicated to Malcolm X or submit a link of your own. CMG Worldwide is the exclusive business representative for the Estate of Malcolm X. We work with companies around the world who wish to use the name or likeness of Malcolm X in any commercial fashion. Visit the Official Store for books and video! Start your own Malcolm X collection today.
  X, Malcolm, 1925-1965; Black nationalism |z United States.
- Marquit, Erwin Archived Website, May 16, 2014-ongoing; Marquit, Erwin
  Erwin Marquit is a professor emeritus of physics at the University of Minnesota. He studied dialectical materialism and philosophy of the natural sciences. He is a longtime member of the Communist Party USA (joined in 1946), active on both the local (Organizational Secretary, Minnesota/Dakotas District) and national levels (International Department and Economics Commission). He was also a founder of the Midwest-based 501(c)(3) Marxist Educational Press (MEP—1976-2011) and editor of the 20 volumes of the Marxist Studies quarterly journal Nature, Society (NST--1986-2007). The website contains selected articles and his memoir.
  Communists |z United States.; Philosophy, Marxist
- Martin, R. Paul (Back of the Book) Archived Website, Jun 19, 2012 - ongoing; Martin, R. Paul
  Glib.com is the official website of R. Paul Martin, the radio host of the Back of the Book program on WBAI and pro-free speech on the web. The website contains links to the biweekly program, information on Pacifica local station boards meetings, and a photo gallery.
  WBAI Radio (New York, N.Y.).; Radio programs--United States.
- McGowan, Daniel Archived Website, Aug 18, 2010 - Feb 18, 2015; McGowan, Daniel, Friends of Daniel McGowan
  This website is a support website for Daniel McGowan. He is an American environmental and social justice activist who was arrested and charged in federal court on multiple counts of arson and conspiracy, relating to the arson of Superior Lumber company in Glendale, Oregon on January 2, 2001 and Jefferson Poplar Farms in Clatskanie, Oregon on May 21, 2001 claimed by the Earth Liberation Front (ELF). McGowan was facing a minimum of life in prison if convicted when he accepted a non- cooperation plea agreement, pleading guilty on November 9, 2006. His arrest is part of what the US government has dubbed Operation Backfire. He was sentenced to 7 years in prison on June 4, 2007 and began serving his time on July 2, 2007 at MDC Brooklyn. The website works to raise awareness and funds for McGowan and work for his freedom.
  Direct action.; Environmentalists |z United States.; Political prisoners |z United States.; Terrorism.
- MichaelMoore.com Archived Website, Sep 2, 2010 - ongoing; Moore, Michael, 1954 Apr. 23-
  Michael Moore (b. 1954) is an American filmmaker, documentarian, author, social critic and activist. He is the director of many documentaries, including "Roger and Me," "Bowling for Columbine," "Fahrenheit 9/11," and "Sicko." This is his official website, which contains his blog, links to other activist websites, and action campaigns.
  Liberals |z United States.; Social justice |z United States.; Social responsibility of business.; Working class |z United States.
- Michael Parenti Political Archive Archived Website, Jul 29, 2009 - ongoing; Parenti, Michael.
  Michael Parenti (b. 1933) is an American political scientist, historian, activist, and culture critic who has been writing on a wide range of both scholarly and popular subjects for over forty years. He has taught at several universities and colleges and has been a frequent guest lecturer before campus and community audiences. The website contains a listing of his books, articles, speeches, and recorded talks.
  Democracy |z United States.; Imperialism |z United States.; Radicals |z United States.
- Moloney, Mick Archived Website, Apr 11, 2014-ongoing; Moloney, Mick (Michael)
  Dr. Mick Moloney (1944-) is a musician, folklorist, and Global Distinguished Professor of Music and Irish Studies at New York University. He immigrated to the United States in 1973, earning a Ph.D. in folklore and folklife from the University of Pennsylvania. He has recorded and produced over forty albums of traditional music, acted as advisor for scores of festivals and concerts, and served as artistic director for the musical ensemble The Green Fields of America. In 1999, Moloney was awarded the National Heritage Award of the National Endowment of the Arts, the highest official honor of traditional artist can receive in the United States. The website includes event and concert listings, his discography, reviews, and his writings.
  Irish Americans |x Music.; Irish |x Music.; Irish |x Songs and music.; Irish |z United States |x Songs and music.
- Munk, Michael Archived Website, Jul 8, 2011; Munk, Michael, 1934-
  Michael Munk, born in Prague in 1934, was a political science professor and a historian of radicalism, focusing mainly on the Pacific Northwest, including via his book, The Portland Red Guide. This website released yearly news releases with commentary by Munk.
  Radicals.
- Nader, Ralph Archived Website, Feb 4, 2012 - ongoing
  Ralph Nader (b. 1934) is an American political activist, as well as an author, lecturer, and attorney. Areas of particular concern to Nader include consumer protection, humanitarianism, environmentalism, and democratic government. Nader is a five-time candidate for President of the United States, having run as a write-in candidate in the 1992 New Hampshire Democratic primary, as the Green Party nominee in 1996 and 2000, and as an independent candidate in 2004 and 2008. The website contains a book list and editorials and opinion pieces by Nader.
  Nader, Ralph; Consumer movements; Consumer protection.
- Nestor Makhno Archive Archived Website, Jul 10, 2012 - Oct 9, 2013; Makhno, Nestor.
  This website contains the writings of Nestor Makhno (1888- 1934), a Ukrainian anarcho-communist guerrilla leader.
  Anarchists.; Communists.
- Olliff, Kevin Archived Website, Aug 18, 2010 - Feb 17, 2011; Olliff, Kevin, Support Kevin Olliff
  SupportKevin.org was a website in support of Kevin Olliff, an animal rights activist who was arrested on April 18th, 2009 on ten felony charges. On Friday, March 19, 2010 Kevin entered a plea of "No Contest" to six of the ten felony charges against him. In a non-cooperation plea agreement, the remaining charges were dismissed and Olliff was released from prison in November 2010.
  Animal rights activists |z United States.; Direct action.; Political prisoners |z United States.
- Ollman, Bertell (Dialectical Marxism) Archived Website, Aug 13, 2009 - Feb 20, 2013; Ollman, Bertell.
  Bertell Ollman is a professor of politics at NYU. Since 1970, he has given about 250 lectures on different aspects of Marxist theory in a dozen countries and has written and edited fifteen books, including Alienation: Marx's Conception of Man in Capitalist Society, Social and Sexual Revolution: Essays on Marx and Reich, Dialectical Investigations, How to Take an Exam...and Remake the World, and most recently Dance of the Dialectic: Steps in Marx's Method. He is also the creator of Class Struggle, the world's first Marxist board game, and from 1978-1983 was president of Class Struggle, Inc., the company that produced and marketed the game. In 1978, after being offered and then denied the chairmanship of the Government Department at the University of Maryland, he became the principal in one of the most important academic freedom struggles of the last half century. The website contains information on his publications, interviews, and directions to Class Struggle.
  College teachers' |z United States.; Communism.; Dialectical materialism.
- Penley, John Archived Website, Mar 15, 2013 - ongoing; Penley, John.
  John Penley is a photographer and grassroots political activist associated with the squatters' rights movement and housing protests of the 1980s and 1990s in New York City's East Village and Lower East Side, as well as numerous other social causes. A former Navy serviceman, Penley took up photography as part of an effort to document the demonstrations, protests, and other political actions in which he took part, and in the process became a photojournalist. Hundreds of Penley's photographs have appeared in in publications including the New York Daily News, the New York Post, the New York Times, New York and Long Island Newsday, New York Magazine, The Villager, High Times Magazine, The Guardian, Art In America, WW 3 Illustrated, The Shadow, the East Village Eye, and many small political publications. They have also been distributed through press services such as United Press International and the Associated Press. The website contains photographs taken by Penley.
  Documentary photography |z New York (State) |z New York.; Photographers |z New York (State) |z New York.; Photojournalism--United States.
- Potter, Will (Green Is The New Red) Archived Website, May 3, 2011 - ongoing; Potter, Will
  Green is the New Red, is the environmental blog of Will Potter, an independent journalist based in Washington D.C. and the author of Green Is the New Red: An Insider’s Account of a Social Movement Under Siege. The blog focuses on how animal rights and environmental activists are being labeled "eco-terrorists," and comparing it to the Red Scare by calling it the "Green Scare."
  Ecoterrorism |x United States.; Environmentalists |x Civil rights.; Green movement.; Political prisoners.
- Reich, Robert Archived Website, Nov 6, 2013 - ongoing; Reich, Robert B.
  This website is the official site of Robert Reich (1946-), a political economist, writer, professor, political commentator, and the former Secretary of Labor under the Clinton Administration. The website contains his blog posts, speaking schedule, videos, and information on his books and films.
  Capitalism.; Economists.; Labor economics.; Welfare economics.
- Reich, Robert for EconoMonitor Archived Website, Feb 5, 2013 - ongoing
  Robert Reich is the nation's 22nd Secretary of Labor and a professor at the University of California at Berkeley. This website contains his blog postings on currrent event labor and labor economics related issues.
  Reich, Robert B.; Capitalism.; Economists.; Labor economics.; Welfare economics.
- Reverend Billy and The Church of Life After Shopping Archived Website, Feb 18, 2010 - ongoing; Talen, Bill.
  The Church of Life After Shopping (or the Church of Earthalujah), founded in 1996, is an activist performance group based in New York City, led by Reverend Billy. Using the form of a revival meeting, on sidewalks and in chain stores, Reverend Billy and his gospel choir exhort consumers to abandon the products of large corporations and mass media; the group also preaches a broader message of economic justice, environmental protection, and anti-militarism, protesting sweatshops and the Iraq War. The website contains event and campaign listings.
  Commodity fetishism.; Consumerism.; Satire, American.; The Immediate Life.
- Rogovin, Milton Archived Website, Sep 9, 2010; Rogovin, Milton, 1909-2011.